[
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the recently launched scheme designed to enhance agricultural productivity, promote crop diversification, and strengthen post-harvest storage at panchayat and block levels?",
        "options": [
            "PM Kisan Samman Nidhi Yojana",
            "PM Krishi Vikas Yojana",
            "PM Fasal Bima Yojana",
            "PM Dhan Dhanya Krishi Yojana",
            "PM SVANIDHI"
        ],
        "answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which region has been projected by the WHO to witness an 85% increase in cancer cases and deaths by 2050?",
        "options": [
            "Africa",
            "Europe",
            "North America",
            "South-East Asia",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where will India open a new Consulate during PM Modi's visit to France in February 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Nice",
            "Marseille",
            "Lyon",
            "Toulouse",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which university's researchers discovered the new phytopathogenic fungus Epicoccum indicum, associated with an emerging leaf spot disease in Chrysopogon zizanioides (vetiver)?",
        "options": [
            "Punjab University",
            "Banaras Hindu University",
            "Jawaharlal Nehru University",
            "University of Hyderabad",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which payment system remains the major driver of digital payments in India as per the recent report February 2025?",
        "options": [
            "IMPS",
            "NEFT",
            "UPI",
            "All of the above",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "UPI"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who from Rajasthan has been shortlisted for the USD 1 million GEMS Education Global Teacher Prize 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Mohammad Imran Khan Mewati",
            "Dr. Ramesh Kumar",
            "Shalini Gupta",
            "Rajesh Kumar",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "Mohammad Imran Khan Mewati"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who won the Tata Steel Masters Chess Tournament 2025 by defeating D Gukesh in the tiebreaker?",
        "options": [
            "Vincent Keymer",
            "R Praggnanandhaa",
            "Arjun Erigaisi",
            "Wei Yi",
            "Magnus Carlsen"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who became the first Black woman to win the Mrs World title in the competition's 40-year history?",
        "options": [
            "Tshego Gaelae",
            "Relebogile Mabotja",
            "Zozibini Tunzi",
            "Shudu Musida",
            "Rabia Fateh"
        ],
        "answer": "Tshego Gaelae"
    },
    {
        "question": "By what percentage has India's fruit and vegetable exports increased in the last five years, as per the Ministry of Commerce and Industry?",
        "options": [
            "35.8%",
            "50.1%",
            "47.3%",
            "41.5%",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the world's largest iceberg that is set to strike South Georgia Island?",
        "options": [
            "Iceberg B15",
            "Iceberg A23a",
            "Iceberg C19",
            "Iceberg D16",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state has been allocated â‚¹23,778 crore for railway projects in the Budget 2025-26?",
        "options": [
            "Bihar",
            "Uttar Pradesh",
            "Maharashtra",
            "Lucknow",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the full form of VSHORAD in the context of DRDO's missile system?",
        "options": [
            "Very Small High-Output Radar Air Defence",
            "Very Short-Range Air Defence",
            "Variable Spectrum High-Range Air Defence",
            "Vertical Strike Hypersonic Operational Radar Air Defence",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Recently, Marcus Stoinis has announced his retirement from ODIs, ending a 74-match career. Which country does he hail from?",
        "options": [
            "South Africa",
            "England",
            "Australia",
            "New Zealand",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Indian research institute developed the novel high-entropy alloy (HEA) catalyst for green hydrogen production?",
        "options": [
            "Indian Institute of Technology (IIT) Madras",
            "Indian Institute of Science (IISc)",
            "Bhabha Atomic Research Centre (BARC)",
            "Centre for Nano and Soft Matter Sciences (CeNS)",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where in West Asia is the Medlab Middle East 2025 exhibition being held?",
        "options": [
            "Riyadh, Saudi Arabia",
            "Dubai, UAE",
            "Doha, Qatar",
            "Khartoum, Sudan",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the Indian-origin artist who won the Grammy Award for Best New Age, Ambient, or Chant Album in 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Ricky Kej",
            "Anoushka Shankar",
            "Chandrika Tandon",
            "Radhika Vekaria",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the new radio series launched by Akashvani on Basant Panchami to promote Indian classical music?",
        "options": [
            "Swar Bharat",
            "Raag Sarita",
            "Sangeet Mala",
            "Har Kanthh Mein Bharat",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "question": "Recently SCO Secretary General holds talks with MEA Secretary, Who is the current Secretary-General of the Shanghai Cooperation Organization (SCO)?",
        "options": [
            "Zhang Ming",
            "Nurlan Yermekbayev",
            "Sergey Lavrov",
            "Wang Yi",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is organizing WAVES 2025, which will introduce AI solutions for live misinformation detection?",
        "options": [
            "NITI Aayog and MeitY",
            "IT Ministry and ICEA",
            "RBI and Digital India Corporation",
            "Ministry of Home Affairs and NIC",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following states has contributed significantly to India's total utility-scale solar installations as per the recent achievement of 100 GW solar power capacity?",
        "options": [
            "Rajasthan, Gujarat, Tamil Nadu, Maharashtra, and Madhya Pradesh",
            "Andhra Pradesh, Telangana, Chhattisgarh, Odisha, and Assam",
            "Kerala, Karnataka, Punjab, Haryana, and West Bengal",
            "Bihar, Jharkhand, Uttar Pradesh, Uttarakhand, and Himachal Pradesh",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "Rajasthan, Gujarat, Tamil Nadu, Maharashtra, and Madhya Pradesh"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where was the National Institute of Electronics and Information Technology (NIELIT) Centre of Excellence in Chip Design inaugurated which is aimed to bolster India's VLSI & semiconductor capabilities?",
        "options": [
            "Bengaluru",
            "Hyderabad",
            "Noida",
            "Chennai",
            "Mumbai"
        ],
        "answer": "Noida"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country has decided to end aid programs for Bangladesh, Albania, and Zambia due to a reduced foreign aid budget?",
        "options": [
            "Germany",
            "Switzerland",
            "France",
            "Sweden",
            "Japan"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which South-East Asian country declared a food security emergency to curb soaring rice prices in 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Vietnam",
            "Thailand",
            "Indonesia",
            "Philippines",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the theme of World Wetlands Day 2025 celebrated at Parvati Arga Ramsar Site in Gonda, Uttar Pradesh?",
        "options": [
            "Wetlands and Water",
            "Protecting Wetlands for our Common Future",
            "Wetlands and Biodiversity",
            "Sustainable Wetlands for a Better Tomorrow",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the venue for the 9th Asian Winter Games 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Seoul, South Korea",
            "Quezon City, Philippines",
            "Harbin, China",
            "New Delhi, India",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Recently government has said 864 km of India-Bangladesh border yet to be fenced in loksabha, Which force is responsible for guarding the India-Bangladesh border?",
        "options": [
            "Assam Rifles",
            "Border Security Force (BSF)",
            "Indo-Tibetan Border Police (ITBP)",
            "National Security Guard (NSG)",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "How much did India contribute to the United Nations Regular Budget for the year 2025?",
        "options": [
            "$25.34 million",
            "$37.64 million",
            "$40.12 million",
            "$50.91 million",
            "$66.91 million"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country became the first in Africa to eliminate onchocerciasis (river blindness) as a public health problem?",
        "options": [
            "Niger",
            "Kenya",
            "South Africa",
            "Democratic Republic of Congo",
            "Eritrea"
        ],
        "answer": "Niger"
    },
    {
        "question": "Former world number one and two-time Grand Slam winner Simona Halep announced her retirement from professional tennis in February 2025. Which country does she hail from?",
        "options": [
            "Albania",
            "Croatia",
            "Romania",
            "Germany",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "Romania"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which project led to the creation of a new map of the Arctic Ocean, revealing an area twice the size of France and six times the size of England?",
        "options": [
            "Ocean Discovery 2050",
            "Seabed 2030",
            "Arctic Exploration Initiative",
            "Deep Sea Mapping Project",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country announced a 25% retaliatory tariff on American imports in response to U.S. trade policies?",
        "options": [
            "China",
            "Canada",
            "Mexico",
            "Germany",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Recently, Digi Yatra app user base has crossed 10 million+ with 30,000 daily downloads. The app was launched in which year?",
        "options": [
            "2014",
            "2022",
            "2021",
            "2023",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "2022"
    },
    {
        "question": "On which date was the PM Internship Scheme launched?",
        "options": [
            "September 15, 2024",
            "October 3, 2024",
            "November 10, 2024",
            "January 9, 2025",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    }
]